♪I wrote a stroke♪
♪كتبتُ ضربةً♪
♪About you and me♪
♪عنك وعني♪
♪You pass like the wind♪
♪ تمرّين كالريح ♪
♪I follow like a leaf♪
أتبعها كالأوراق المتساقطة
♪But just you and me♪
♪لكن فقط أنت وأنا♪
♪Had no happy ending♪
♪لم تكن لها نهاية سعيدة♪
♪Perhaps it was just a chance encounter♪
♪ربما كان مجرد لقاء عابر♪
♪I turn memories over with great care♪
♪أُقلّب الذكريات بعناية فائقة♪
♪Afraid to lose the past♪
♪خائف من فقدان الماضي♪
♪Tears fall quietly with the plot♪
♪تتساقط الدموع بهدوء مع تطور الأحداث♪
♪Shattered with no response♪
♪محطمة بلا رد♪
♪The wind once♪
♪الريح ذات مرة♪
♪Through layers of mist♪
♪عبر طبقات من الضباب♪
♪And snowy scenes♪
♪ومشاهد ثلجية♪
♪Gently cradled the leaf in my palm♪
♪أمسكتُ بالورقة برفق في راحة يدي♪
♪But♪
♪لكن♪
♪Winds will cease♪
ستتوقف الرياح
♪Leaves will wither♪
♪ستذبل الأوراق♪
♪Our meeting was too fleeting♪
♪كان لقاؤنا خاطفاً جداً♪
♪It's an unavoidable fate♪
♪إنه مصير لا مفر منه♪
♪I too once♪
♪وأنا أيضاً ذات مرة♪
♪Walked through♪
♪مررنا عبر♪
♪A sea of people♪
♪بحر من الناس♪
♪Unafraid of how far it is♪
♪لا أخشى المسافة♪
♪Racing under stars toward you♪
♪أتسابق تحت النجوم نحوك♪
♪But♪
♪لكن♪
♪Time is heartless♪
♪الزمن قاسٍ بلا رحمة♪
♪You never yield♪
♪لن تستسلم أبداً♪
♪Let love remain♪
♪ليدم الحب♪
=Spring Night=
ليلة الربيع
=Episode 21=
=الحلقة ٢١=
Drink it.
اشربه.
The child in your womb
الطفل الذي في رحمك
cannot be kept.
لا يمكن الاحتفاظ بها.
The Emperor has issued an edict.
أصدر الإمبراطور مرسوماً.
Such is fate.
هكذا هو القدر.
I do not
لا أفعل
believe in fate.
آمن بالقدر.
Seeing you have such resolve,
بما أنك تتمتع بهذه العزيمة،
I can rest easy.
يمكنني أن أرتاح بالاً.
Because I do not
لأنني لا أفعل
believe in fate either.
لا تؤمن بالقدر أيضاً.
Why?
لماذا؟
Why him?
لماذا هو؟
He killed our father.
لقد قتل والدنا.
One of us has to die.
لا بد أن يموت أحدنا.
The killer was the Emperor.
كان القاتل هو الإمبراطور.
Not Ye Wuming.
ليس يي وومينغ.
Nian...
ملكنا...
Zhifeng.
تشيفنغ.
I understand what you mean.
أفهم ما تقصده.
But Ye Wuming and I...
لكن أنا ويي وومينغ...
No.
لا.
The Crown Prince and I
ولي العهد وأنا
have no future.
ليس لديهم مستقبل.
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
I want to go home.
أريد العودة إلى المنزل.
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك.
Zhifeng,
تشيفنغ،
let me be alone for a while.
دعوني أبقى وحدي لبعض الوقت.
(Shen Mansion)
(قصر شين)
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Father.
أب.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Come.
يأتي.
Nian.
لنا.
If someday,
إذا حدث ذلك يوماً ما،
something bad happens to me,
يحدث لي شيء سيء،
remember this.
تذكر هذا.
Dig up this box.
احفر هذا الصندوق.
Find a chance
ابحث عن فرصة
to give what's inside
أن تعطي ما بداخلك
to the Emperor.
إلى الإمبراطور.
Do you understand?
هل تفهم؟
This is evidence of exam fraud
هذا دليل على الغش في الامتحانات
discovered by my father.
اكتشفه والدي.
(So my father)
(إذن والدي)
(was framed and our family was executed)
(تم تلفيق التهمة لنا وأُعدمت عائلتنا)
(because he found evidence)
(لأنه وجد دليلاً)
(of Qiu Xuanling)
(من تشيو شوانلينغ)
(manipulating the exams.)
(التلاعب بالامتحانات.)
Shen Jinyuan's daughter,
ابنة شين جينيوان،
Shen Zhinian's here.
شين زينيان هنا.
Prime Minister's word.
هذا كلام رئيس الوزراء.
Kill her! Go!
اقتلوها! انطلقوا!
- Yes!
- نعم!
You guys, over there.
يا رفاق، هناك.
You guys,
يا رفاق،
- go that way! - Yes!
- اذهب من هذا الطريق! - نعم!
- You guys follow me!
- هل تتابعونني يا رفاق؟
Here.
هنا.
Not here.
ليس هنا.
That way!
بهذه الطريقة!
Yes!
نعم!
Don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
It's me.
هذا أنا.
It's dangerous here.
الوضع هنا خطير.
We need to leave quickly.
علينا المغادرة بسرعة.
♪We made a pact♪
♪ لقد عقدنا اتفاقاً ♪
♪It's hard to obtain a wish♪
♪من الصعب تحقيق الأمنية♪
♪So close♪
♪قريب جدًا♪
♪We keep silent♪
♪نلتزم الصمت♪
♪Leaving one alone♪
♪ترك المرء وشأنه♪
♪Looking back now♪
♪بالنظر إلى الماضي الآن♪
♪Between heaven and earth♪
♪بين السماء والأرض♪
♪How to remember♪
♪كيفية التذكر♪
♪How to say goodbye♪
♪كيف نقول وداعاً♪
♪Back then♪
♪في ذلك الوقت♪
♪It was illusion♪
♪كان ذلك وهماً♪
♪Or it was real♪
♪أو كان حقيقياً♪
♪It was windy and snowy♪
♪كان الجو عاصفاً ومثلجاً♪
♪It was pure and bright♪
♪كانت نقية ومشرقة♪
♪Remembering a past life♪
♪تذكر حياة سابقة♪
♪Without regret♪
♪بدون ندم♪
♪Read this scroll♪
♪اقرأ هذه اللفافة♪
You know everything?
هل تعرف كل شيء؟
♪When we meet again♪
♪عندما نلتقي مجدداً♪
♪Leaving one alone♪
♪ترك المرء وشأنه♪
♪Looking back now♪
♪بالنظر إلى الماضي الآن♪
Mai Tian.
ماي تيان.
♪How to remember♪
♪كيفية التذكر♪
♪How to say goodbye♪
♪كيف نقول وداعاً♪
♪Back then♪
♪في ذلك الوقت♪
♪It was illusion♪
♪كان ذلك وهماً♪
♪Or it was real♪
♪أو كان حقيقياً♪
♪It was windy and snowy♪
♪كان الجو عاصفاً ومثلجاً♪
♪It was pure and bright♪
♪كانت نقية ومشرقة♪
♪Remembering a past life♪
♪تذكر حياة سابقة♪
♪Without regret♪
♪بدون ندم♪
♪Read this scroll♪
♪اقرأ هذه اللفافة♪
Look out!
انتبه!
♪The wind drifts alone and free♪
♪الريح تنجرف وحيدة وحرة♪
♪Through seasons, none asks of me♪
♪على مرّ الفصول، لا أحد يطلب مني♪
♪Spring fades, and autumn wails♪
♪يتلاشى الربيع، ويبكي الخريف♪
♪Only the waning moon lights my solitude♪
♪لا ينير عزلتي إلا ضوء القمر المتضائل ♪
♪Love arose with the wind's sigh♪
♪نشأ الحب مع زفرة الريح♪
♪On a cold night, a swan's shadow flashes by♪
♪في ليلة باردة، يمر ظل بجعة سريعًا♪
♪You're deeply devoted♪
♪أنت شديد الإخلاص♪
♪Yet spring wind betrayed your heart♪
لكن رياح الربيع خانت قلبك.
♪I miss you so much♪
♪أفتقدك كثيراً♪
♪I never forget you♪
♪لن أنساك أبداً♪
♪A brief period of love-sickness♪
♪ فترة قصيرة من ألم الحب ♪
♪You won my heart over♪
لقد فزتَ بقلبي!
♪Why did we first meet♪
♪لماذا التقينا لأول مرة؟♪
♪Seeking spring's song and night whispers♪
♪أبحث عن أغنية الربيع وهمسات الليل♪
♪Long autumn comes, and wild geese southward fly♪
♪يأتي الخريف الطويل، وتهاجر الأوز البرية جنوباً♪
♪The azure clouds know my name♪
♪السحب الزرقاء تعرف اسمي♪
♪I remember you, and you understand me♪
أتذكرك، وأنت تفهمني
♪Watching the sun set♪
♪مشاهدة غروب الشمس♪
♪Autumn departs, and beauty fades away♪
يرحل الخريف، ويتلاشى الجمال.
♪To lean on you once more someday♪
♪لأعتمد عليك مرة أخرى يوماً ما♪